《夜班经理》前情提要
我们的雇主要跻身顶层
Our paymasters want us at the top table,
难免要踩着他人的脑袋上位
we may have to stand on some heads to get there.
该死 我的投资人出资
Shit. My investors chuck in,
几亿的资金
what, a few hundred million?
然后他们得到了一个国家?
And in return they get a whole country.
铜矿 石油 锂矿 这不就是下金蛋的鹅吗?
Copper, oil, lithium. I mean, that's the golden goose, right?
你说不认识泰迪
You told me you didn't know Teddy.
要么被引渡到英国 终身监禁 要么帮我打进内部
Extradition to the UK and a life in prison. Will you get me on the inside?
如果他发现 一定会杀了我
If he finds out, he will kill me.
我六岁的时候我父亲就死了 我亲眼看他们把他扔在门口
My father died when I was six. I watched them dump him at the gates.
泰迪是个野性之人 他不适合文明社会
Teddy's a cowboy. He's not fit for civilised company.
他是我唯一的儿子和继承人
Danny is my only son and heir.
是不是你偷了货物清单?
Did you steal the shipment list?
联系最高法院负责人
Calling the head of the Supreme Court.
康苏埃洛有权下令打开那批货
Consuelo has the authority to open the shipment.
泰迪!嘿!
Hey!
出事了
Everything's gone wrong.
那个香港投资人... 你还好吗?
The Hong Kong investor. Okay?
...我要他的照片
I want his picture.
亚历克斯古德温
亚历克斯古德温 又名安德鲁伯奇
Alex Goodwin, also known as Andrew Birch.
他的名字是乔纳森派恩
His name is Jonathan Pine.
他人在哥伦比亚 他已经盯上我们了
He's in Colombia, and he's onto our arrangement.
你想让我做什么?
What do you want me to do?
他在这里和伦敦都有支援
He'll have support teams here and in London.
找出来 处理掉
Identify them and deal with them.
那派恩呢?他现在在哪儿?
And Pine? Where is he now?
把他交给我
Leave him to me.
《夜班经理 第二季》
本剧集由米奇爸爸
基于Amazon官方译文制作
改根据约翰勒卡雷小说改编
我们继续今天的新闻
Let's continue with today's news.
塞巴斯蒂安 你有什么消息吗?
Sebastián, what have you got?
谢谢你 胡里奥 是的
Thanks, Julio. Exactly.
刺杀亚历杭德罗瓜特罗斯的 是一名前游击队员
The assassin of Alejandro Gualteros is an ex-guerrilla member
曾参与过多年的武装战斗
who spent several years in armed combat.
奥克塔维奥佩雷斯目前在逃 被认为是极度危险人物
Octavio Pérez is on the run and considered highly dangerous.
谢谢你 塞巴斯蒂安 抱歉打断一下...
Thanks, Sebastián. Sorry to interrupt...
还有多远?
How much further?
几个小时吧
A couple hours.
哥伦比亚 麦德林
这是一场针对亚历杭德罗瓜特罗斯的 残酷而冷血的袭击
This was a brutal and cynical attack against Alejandro Gualteros.
亚历杭德罗瓜特罗斯为我国的正义 奋斗了一生
Alejandro tirelessly campaigned for justice in this country.
我们目前处于高度警戒状态
We are at a heightened level of risk.
因此我会下令提升安保等级
I am therefore raising security levels.
未知号码
你收到红色警报了吗?
Did you receive the red flag?
收到了 你动身了吗?
Yeah. Are you moving?
我正准备动身
Yeah, I'm just about to.
你怎么还没走?现在立刻去机场
Why haven't you gone already? Get to the airport now.
用我给你的出境通行证 好
Use the exit parcel provided. Okay.
喂 是我 恐怕我要取消我们的会面了
Yes. It's me. I'm afraid I'm going to have to cancel our appointment.
我这边有客人
I have guests.
我会把我的调查结果留给你 盖着邮戳的A4横线纸
I'll leave you my findings. Postmarked, of course. On A4 lined paper.
卡拉佩蒂安先生
Mr Karapetian.
是 有什么事吗?
Yes. How can I help?
需要帮忙吗? 不必 谢谢
Can I help you? No, thanks.
他有笔脏钱需要洗白
He had money that needed cleaning.
是他从一家瑞士家族银行偷来的
He stole it from a Swiss family bank.
正好我们需要钱
It is what we needed.
泰迪 我不是早就告诉你...
Did I not tell you...?
我们需要那笔该死的钱 不是吗? 或者你有更好的办法吗 混蛋?
We needed the fucking money, didn't we? Or do you have any better ideas, asshole?
说英文!
Speak English!
你们听好了
Let me tell you something about the man you've been dealing with.
和你们打交道的这个人
他不是什么瑞士银行家 也不是香港投资人
He's not a Swiss banker. He's not a Hong Kong investor.
更不会在煤矿乐队里吹短笛
He doesn't play the piccolo in a colliery band.
他是英国情报特工
He is a British intelligence agent
擅长挖掘别人自己都不知道的信息
with an indecent habit of getting information people barely knew they had.
很多人都栽在他这招上
Many had been susceptible to this gift.
我敢打赌罗克珊娜博拉尼奥斯 也逃不掉
And I'd lay money that Roxana Bolaños could be added to that list.
你呢 泰迪? 你是不是也被他套住了?
What about you, Teddy? Were you susceptible?
你这是什么意思?
What do you mean?
回答我 你被他套话了吗?
Answer the question. Were you susceptible?
我什么都没跟马修埃利斯说 他也一无所获
I told Matthew Ellis nothing. And he has achieved nothing.
检察官已经死了
The prosecutor is dead.
我们会放行货物 交给卡布瑞拉家族
We will release the cargo and deliver it to the Cabreras.
一切都按计划进行
So everything is as we planned.
是吗 计划可是没有差错
No, the plan was no mistakes.
你在哪儿 乔纳森?
Where are you, Jonathan?
你确定这里安全吗?
Are you sure it's safe here?
自从我父亲被杀后就没人来过这里
Mm-hmm. Nobody's been here since my father was killed.
马丁 我是麦克斯
收到新录音 收听
你应该听听这个 罗宾逊先生
You should listen to this, Mr Robinson.
你们听好了 和你们打交道的这个人
Let me explain something about the man you've been dealing with.
他不是什么瑞士银行家 也不是香港投资人
He's not a Swiss banker. He's not a Hong Kong investor.
更不会在煤矿乐队里吹短笛
He doesn't play the piccolo in a colliery band.
他是英国情报特工 擅长挖掘...
He is a British intelligence agent with an indecent habit of getting...
你叫奥克塔维奥 对吗?
Your name is Octavio, right?
大家都叫我塔沃
People call me Tavo.
你有能联系上的家人吗?
Do you have family you can call?
你在这会很安全
You're going to be safe here.
等我把这事儿解决了
Until I sort this out.
好吗?
Okay?
别留我和她在一起
Don't leave me with her.
他们是一伙的
She's one of them.
没关系 她是我们这边的
It's all right. She's on our side.
在这等着
Wait here.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
能不能告诉我是怎么回事?
You want to tell me what's going on?
你知道的那个吉尔伯托汉森
The man you know as Gilberto Hanson...
他是个英国军火商
He's an English arms dealer.
我和他 有些渊源
And he and I have... history.
现在他知道我在这了
And now he knows I'm here.
所以我得在他找到我之前先去找他
So, I have to get to him before he gets to me.
你的团队呢?他们在哪儿? 根本就没什么团队
What about your team? Where are they? There is no team.
你告诉我你有支援的
You told me you had support.
其实根本没有
Well, there's no one.
就我一个人
I'm alone.
那我之前提的保证呢?
What about the guarantees I asked for?
我什么都给不了你
I can't give you any of those.
你耍我
You played me.
为了打入他们内部 我不得不这么做
I did what was necessary to get on the inside.
我把命都交给你了
I trusted you with my life.
你知道如果泰迪找到我 他会对我做什么吗?
Do you have any idea what Teddy will do to me if he finds me?
所以你必须待在这里
Which is why I need you to stay here.
关掉手机
Keep your phone off.
千万别让塔沃露面 他们会找他的
Make sure Tavo stays out of sight. They'll be looking for him.
他是谋杀嫌疑人 罗克珊娜 我说真的
He's wanted for murder. Roxana, I'm serious.
现在又开始担心塔沃了 是吗
It's Tavo that we're worried about?
听着 是你选择和那些人合作的
Listen, you chose to work with these people.
你清楚你卷进了什么
You knew what you were getting involved with.
我会想办法让你脱身 但别指望我心存感激
Now, I will get you out of this. But do not ask me to be grateful.
你从一开始接近我就是在算计这个
You planned this from the minute you approached me.
不
No.
你骗了我 故意把我拖下水
You lied to me. You deliberately compromised me.
现在我无处可去
And now I have nowhere to go.
我骗了你?
I lied to you?
那我跟你讲讲瓦利德吧
Let me tell you about a man called Waleed.
他是我的朋友 他有三个孩子
He was my friend. He had three children.
他喜欢打板球 最终流血身亡 死在了我怀里 都是因为你骗了我!
He loved cricket. And he bled out in my arms because you lied to me.
你帮我只有一个原因
You helped me for one reason and one reason only,
就是为了你自己
which is to save your own skin.
我觉得
I think...
你也很喜欢我 不是吗?
you... like my skin, don't you?
待在这
Stay here.
我会回来的
I'll come back.
随你便吧
Do what you want.
我再也不会求你了
I will never ask anything of you ever again.
英国 伦敦
把我弄这来做什么?
What am I doing here?
我想和你聊聊亚历克斯古德温的下落
I want to talk to you about Alex Goodwin's whereabouts.
亚历克斯已经死了
Alex is dead.
没错 你之前说过
Yeah, you said.
你要把他的尸体从西班牙带回来
You were returning his body from Spain.
没错
That's right.
炸成渣了 是吗?
Not much of it, was there?
这是昨天在麦德林拍到的
Taken just yesterday in Medellín.
你一直在秘密监视这栋房子 巴兹尔
You've been secretly filming this house, Basil.
你还去接近亚当霍利维尔 骗他把手机给你
And you met Adam Holywell and tricked him into giving you his phone.
雷克斯葬礼之后 在教堂里 你对我承诺过
In the church after Rex's funeral you promised me...
你是绝对忠诚的
that you were loyal.
乔纳森派恩在哪里?
Where's Jonathan Pine?
我根本不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
放屁!别骗我
Bullshit. Don't fucking lie to me!
我再问你一遍 乔纳森派恩在哪里?
I'm gonna ask you again. Where is Jonathan Pine?
查理 我们帮他回忆一下 好吗?
Charlie. Let's see if we can jog his memory, shall we?
弗里斯基 你能接电话真是太好了
Frisky. Thank you for answering the call.
为了你 做什么都行 老大
Oh, no. Anything for you, chief.
跟着法蒂玛就行
Battle Boy will show you the way.
运气好还能喝瓶啤酒 最近怎么样?
If you're lucky, you might get a bottle of beer. How you doing?
很好
他们是谁?
Who are they?
家那边的朋友 他们会帮我们找人
Friends from home. They're gonna help us find your boy.
我来就行
Let me do it.
不不
No, no, no.
你来处理货物
You focus on the shipment.
新检察官今早会放行那批货
The new prosecutor's gonna release the cargo this morning.
你飞去卡塔赫纳 把货从港口运出来
Fly to Cartagena. Get the cargo out of that port.
货的事我的手下就能做
That's transportation. I have boys who can do that.
泰迪 听着
Teddy, listen to me.
被复仇蒙蔽的人最后只会毁了自己
A man hell-bent on revenge guarantees only his own demise.
我们得专注当下的任务
You and I have to focus on the task at hand.
何塞卡布瑞拉 周年日
José Cabrera, the anniversary.
美洲之王 还记得吗?
Kings of America, remember?
接电话
Answer it.
是谁?
Who's this?
让他听电话
Put him on.
你真是让我头大
Well, you are trouble.
山顶餐厅
The hilltop restaurant.
我用安德鲁伯奇的名字订了位
I booked a table under the name of Andrew Birch.
下午一点 一个人来
1 p.m. Come alone.
汉森先生 您的朋友已经到了 抱歉我没来得及清场
Mr Hanson, your friend is already here. Sorry I couldn't clear the restaurant.
不用 别担心 圣地亚哥
No, no. Don't you worry, Santiago.
安德鲁是我在伦敦的老同事 是个了不起的人
Andrew's an old colleague from London. Top man.
他在那边 谢谢
Okay, sir. Thank you.
安德鲁
Andrew.
吉尔伯托
Gilberto.
好久不见
Been too long.
您要点些什么吗?
Can I get you anything, sir?
两杯你这最好的果汁
Uh... Two of your delicious juices.
菜单就免了 我俩都要牛排
And don't bother with menus. We'll both have the steak.
我要见血的那种 好的 先生
And I want to see blood. Sangre! Yes, sir.
好的
Okay, sir.
我得提醒你一句 这家餐厅是我朋友开的
I should probably warn you that this place is owned by a pal.
你要敢乱来 可不会有好下场
So if you try anything, you will come badly unstuck.
所以我才选了这里
That's why I chose it.
我想让你觉得安全
I wanted you to feel safe.
可是我
I, on the other hand,
本可以让你在上山的路上 就被一枪爆头
could have had a bullet put in your skull on the drive up here.
但你没有
But you didn't.
你还得下山呢
There's always the drive down.
谢谢
Thank you.
你老了一些
You look older.
但我更聪明了
Yeah. Well, I'm certainly wiser.
杰德怎么样?容光焕发吧?
How's Jed? Glowing, is she?
开罗之后我就没见过她了
I haven't seen her since Cairo.
对她的健康来说也是好事
Well, that's probably best for her health.
还有安吉拉伯尔
And Angela Burr?
你告诉她了吗?
You've spoken to her about all this?
安吉拉伯尔是个懦夫
Angela Burr is a coward.
这话有点过了吧
That's a bit harsh.
她做出了理性的选择 她骗了我
She made an informed choice. She lied to me.
那谁知道你来这了?
So who knows you're here?
没人知道
Nobody.
胡扯
Oh, bollocks.